<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Voctro Labs Archives - VNN</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/voctro-labs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Everything about virtual voices, just one click away!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 15:02:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-VNNLOGOSQUARE3-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Voctro Labs Archives - VNN</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>MAIKAVERSE Album Review</title>
		<link>/maikaverse-album-review/</link>
					<comments>/maikaverse-album-review/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jade Kaiba]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 09:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Album]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voctro Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=159859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After a successful Kickstarter campaign for an art book last year, we have more good news for fans of MAIKA: The MAIKA compilation album, MAIKAVERSE, is now available on Spotify, Google Play, Amazon and iTunes! The new #VOCALOID Album MAIKAVERSE, announced some time ago is already available on Spotify featuring 14 new original @VocaloidMaika songs &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/maikaverse-album-review/">MAIKAVERSE Album Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a successful <a href="/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika-artbook-kickstarter-has-launched/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Kickstarter campaign</a> for an art book last year, we have more good news for fans of <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/13431" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MAIKA</a>: The MAIKA compilation album, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Al/24096" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>MAIKAVERSE</em></a>, is now available on <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2JDYunBofruLHXgFALuRkz?si=ma9_tb7_SC-MyD06_U80Bg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spotify</a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/music/album/Various_Artists_MAIKAVERSE?id=Brvbqstddqu5p4hzn3cq2bx3cte" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Play</a>, <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B078X5RJKG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Amazon</a> and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/album/maikaverse/1333323246" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iTunes</a>!</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">The new <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/VOCALOID?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#VOCALOID</a> Album MAIKAVERSE, announced some time ago is already available on Spotify featuring 14 new original <a href="https://twitter.com/VocaloidMaika?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@VocaloidMaika</a> songs by amazing producers from around the world: <a href="https://t.co/Zx3O3S4ybY">https://t.co/Zx3O3S4ybY</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Voctro Labs (@VoctroLabs) <a href="https://twitter.com/VoctroLabs/status/952651417810034694?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 14, 2018</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>There are 14 songs available in the album, all from different producers with different musical styles.</p>
<p>The tracklist for <em>MAIKAVERSE</em> is as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181175" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Imagínate Mi Amour</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/14665" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CYO Style</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181173" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hyperconectados</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/13257" target="_blank" rel="noopener">YZYX</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181174" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Like Whatever</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/919" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CircusP</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181176" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pedrito</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/15362" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AlexTrip Sands</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181177" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vacío Lleno</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/25180" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VNaneP</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181178" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Incomprehensible</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/49268" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvin Valentin</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181179" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sacrificio</a> by Gurodoll</li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181180" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Infinity</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/9940" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nostraightanswer</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181181" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Nemezis</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/9279" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marvyanaka</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181182" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Días de Estrés</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/46847" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AkuP</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181183" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Half Empty</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/2434" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EmpathP</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181184" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Dimensión</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/25412" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AJ/Music</a></li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/181185" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Escaleras del Saber</a> by Riten Kuroji</li>
<li><a href="http://vocadb.net/S/56734" target="_blank" rel="noopener">La Audición</a> by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/21591" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Maubox</a></li>
</ol>
<p>If you want to listen to the <em>MAIKAVERSE</em> album, you can play it using the Spotify player below, or you can <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2JDYunBofruLHXgFALuRkz" target="_blank" rel="noopener">find it here on Spotify</a>.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/2JDYunBofruLHXgFALuRkz%3Fsi%3Dma9_tb7_SC-MyD06_U80Bg" width="300" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></p>
<h2>Album Review</h2>
<p>Being a MAIKA fan, I (Jade) wanted to listen to the <em>MAIKAVERSE</em> album myself, so here is my own review with my opinions on each of the tracks available.</p>
<p>The first track, &#8220;Imagínate Mi Amour&#8221;, is an EDM track by CYO Style which features seamless transitions between more traditional instruments, such as guitar and drums, to various synthesizers and electronic beats.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hyperconectados&#8221; is another EDM track, this time by YZYX with a more intense and electronic feel. In this song, MAIKA&#8217;s vocals are somewhat distorted to accentuate her synthetic vocals, and the producer has also made her sound like she is speaking in some parts.</p>
<p>The next song, &#8220;Like Whatever&#8221; by CircusP, is also an EDM song which makes use of various synthesizers, distortion of MAIKA&#8217;s vocals in some parts, and even some other vocals to harmonize with in places. The lyrics in this song suggest a character with quite a sassy personality, which is especially noticeable in the spoken line near the end which just exudes attitude.</p>
<p>In contrast to the previous songs, &#8220;Pedrito&#8221; by AlexTrip Sands is a more traditional Latin dance number, which really shows off MAIKA&#8217;s Spanish vocals wonderfully. It&#8217;s hard to resist swaying with the music as you listen! At around 3 minutes in, the tempo kicks up a notch and MAIKA begins to &#8216;speak,&#8217; as if to an audience, and the effect is really quite enchanting.</p>
<p>&#8220;Vacío Lleno&#8221; by VNaneP starts off with beautiful piano track, then gently builds up by adding in synth and then guitar and drums until it feels like an intriguing blend of EDM and rock. The producer handles MAIKA&#8217;s vocals well through the changes in tempo, adding power and effects on the vocals in places to further add complexity.</p>
<p>&#8220;Incomprehensible&#8221; is another rock song, but with more traditional guitar and bass instruments. The song comes in strong from the beginning and maintains a good pace, building and falling where necessary and MAIKA&#8217;s vocals seem particularly powerful in the high notes of the chorus.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sacrificio&#8221; by Gurodoll kicks things up a notch further with a metal track that includes a gorgeous mix of harsh, clean and almost operatic vocals. This is certainly one of the most intense songs on the album. Though MAIKA does not have a Power voice bank or a V4 voice bank with a growl, in some places, you can hear a growl-like strain in her voice that you would expect from a singer if they were performing this kind of song live. I was particularly impressed by the way her vocals were handled by this producer.</p>
<p>&#8220;Infinity&#8221; by Nostraightanswer brings things back down a little with a more mellow track with a laid back beat and lyrics full of longing. When the synthesizers come in, the song becomes almost trance-like and then the beat builds up in the last third of the song and leaves the listener with a more positive message.</p>
<p>&#8220;Nemezis&#8221; by MarvyanakaP begins with an atmospheric string melody, and then heavy drums and guitar are introduced as MAIKA begins to sing. And what a surprise it is when you realize that she is actually singing in Polish! After a short intro, the song turns into a proper rock number while still featuring the classical instruments throughout, giving it a somewhat orchestral quality.</p>
<p>&#8220;Días de Estrés&#8221; by AkuP  starts with a gentle melody which sounds reminiscent of traditional Japanese instruments, but don&#8217;t be fooled! The intense beat and synthesizers come in shortly after and we are back to the realms of EDM. In this song, we hear quite a range of emotions in MAIKA&#8217;s vocals, from soft and gentle to powerful, and even a sort of sing-song voice which gives off more sassy vibes full of attitude. The song closes with the gentle instruments from the beginning again to round things off nicely, as if the song has come full circle.</p>
<p>&#8220;Half Empty&#8221; is a soft rock song from EmpathP which features themes of sex,  drugs and alcohol, which are not typically associated with EmpathP&#8217;s work. EmpathP said during a previous live stream that the song is written from two different perspectives, a woman and a man trying to escape their problems through sex and alcohol respectively. The song is rather cinematic, with the lyrics describing the setting that these characters live in and the situations that they find themselves in, so that the listener almost feels like they are transported into their world.</p>
<p>The next song, &#8220;Dimensión&#8221; by AJ/Music, is another track which blends elements of rock and EDM, with the rock instruments being the most prominent and synthesizers being added in places as more of a melodic highlight. Again, MAIKA&#8217;s vocals are made to sound expressive and powerful in the chorus.</p>
<p>The genre changes once more with &#8220;Escaleras del Saber&#8221; by Riten Kuroji. It begins with what sounds like an old music box melody, and then a gentle, steady beat comes in with whimsical strings that seem reminiscent of traditional French or Russian music. There&#8217;s a melancholic quality to the song, but it seems pleasantly calming.</p>
<p>For the final song on the album, &#8220;La Audición&#8221; by Maubox begins with upbeat acoustic guitar and drums, then gradually brings in piano and tambourine for an additional rhythmic element in the chorus. In the last third of the song, MAIKA&#8217;s vocals sound especially soulful. I felt myself swaying along with the music on more than one occasion.</p>
<p>All in all, I am very impressed with the quality and the variety of the songs on offer in this album with the wide range of musical genres and tuning styles it presents. Each song has it&#8217;s own unique characteristics due to the unique style of the producers who worked on them. I liked each different aspect for different reasons, but all of them were an absolute pleasure to listen to.</p>
<p>But don&#8217;t take my word for it! Be sure to check out the <em>MAIKAVERSE</em> album via one of the links below to experience it yourself.</p>
<h3>Links</h3>
<p><a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2JDYunBofruLHXgFALuRkz?si=ma9_tb7_SC-MyD06_U80Bg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MAIKAVERSE on Spotify</a></p>
<p><a href="https://play.google.com/store/music/album/Various_Artists_MAIKAVERSE?id=Brvbqstddqu5p4hzn3cq2bx3cte" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MAIKAVERSE on Google Play</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B078X5RJKG" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MAIKAVERSE on Amazon</a></p>
<p><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/album/maikaverse/1333323246" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MAIKAVERSE on iTunes</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/maikaverse-album-review/">MAIKAVERSE Album Review</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/maikaverse-album-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voctro Labs Announces Voiceful</title>
		<link>/voctro-labs-announces-voiceful/</link>
					<comments>/voctro-labs-announces-voiceful/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 23:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voctro Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=146429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Voctro Labs has been expanding past VOCALOID for years, and their newest project brings new vocal synthesis technology to your fingertips! Voiceful is an APA program featuring both pre-made voices that are much like voice banks, as well as the ability to turn your own voice into a &#8220;voice bank!&#8221; You can even bring back &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/voctro-labs-announces-voiceful/">Voctro Labs Announces Voiceful</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/989" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voctro Labs</a> has been expanding past VOCALOID for years, and their newest project brings new vocal synthesis technology to your fingertips! <a href="https://www.voiceful.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Voiceful</a> is an APA program featuring both pre-made voices that are much like voice banks, as well as the ability to turn your own voice into a &#8220;voice bank!&#8221; You can even bring back voices from the dead thanks to this new piece of synthesizer technology.</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/91ZCL-4WWTw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>What can you do with Voiceful?</h3>
<h4>Say it with a Song</h4>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cf7gjHcUo-A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Via a mobile app or on the official website, people can enter lyrics and have either a male or female voice sing them! At the moment, only one melody is available in the demo. However, it&#8217;s safe to guess that more will be available as time goes on.</p>
<p>To try the demo, click <a href="https://www.voiceful.io/demo_vosyn.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<h4>Make a celebrity sing</h4>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oHmLO0MN_-Y?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Voiceful can take a voice recording of any person, dead or alive, and build a new voice model for content. You can even turn a speaking voice into a singing one! Voctro&#8217;s example uses audio from Obama&#8217;s speeches to make him sing.</p>
<p>While this feature appears to be only on commission, it&#8217;s sure to bring some interesting things in the future! These voices that can talk and sing can be incredibly useful in advertisements and the like.</p>
<h4>Transform your voice</h4>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_fa8qEjyGLU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>People have been playing with their voices in audio programs for ages. From the demo and preview video, this seems to be a quick way to do some simple voice edits, as well as some pretty impressive and fancier edits. Their male to female voice example sounds absolutely amazing and would allow people to create duets with only one voice.</p>
<p>You can try the technology out for yourself on the demo page <a href="https://www.voiceful.io/demo_votrans.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<h4>Pretend you can sing</h4>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KRx0sLm2GSc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Ever needed to use Autotune but just couldn&#8217;t get the hang of it? Voiceful offers a quick auto tuning option that does all the work for you! You can automatically adjust tuning, timing, and voice quality to make you sound like a professional singer.</p>
<p>You can check out the demo for this function <a href="https://www.voiceful.io/demo_voscale.html#" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<h3>How does it work?</h3>
<p>For all information on how the program works, please check out the website <a href="https://www.voiceful.io/#how" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>. Voctro provides specifics on each part of Voiceful and how it works. Below is a summary of the main points.</p>
<p>Voiceful is a toolkit built to design digital and mobile experiences with speech and singing voices. Their API allows you to develop ideas and integrate them easily into your app, website, game, social network, or products. You can use a Cloud API directly or integrate Voiceful natively in your mobile device, desktop, or server application.</p>
<p>It combines pre-defined features with a series of elements that can be configured for each project including language, background music, or specific technology adaptations. Voctro Labs can also build ideas from scratch if they happen to like them. So feel free to contact them if you&#8217;d like to use Voiceful for a project!</p>
<p>In addition, users can expand Voiceful to have it store and distribute creations made with it for an extra fee.</p>
<h3>More Information</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.voiceful.io/">Official Website</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.voiceful.io/demos.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Demos</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/voctro-labs-announces-voiceful/">Voctro Labs Announces Voiceful</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/voctro-labs-announces-voiceful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The Art of VOCALOID MAIKA&#8221; Artbook Kickstarter Has Launched!</title>
		<link>/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika-artbook-kickstarter-has-launched/</link>
					<comments>/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika-artbook-kickstarter-has-launched/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[R3van]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 05:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voctro Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=142798</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For about two years, the main illustrator of MAIKA, Noriko Hayashi, was thinking of creating an artbook filled with her illustrations of the Spanish VOCALOID. Now, that dream is closer to becoming a reality with the Kickstarter project &#8220;The Art of VOCALOID MAIKA&#8221;. About the Project The book will include: Predesigns Unpublished sketches Unpublished redesigns All &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika-artbook-kickstarter-has-launched/">&#8220;The Art of VOCALOID MAIKA&#8221; Artbook Kickstarter Has Launched!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For about two years, the main illustrator of <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/13431">MAIKA</a>, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/15186">Noriko Hayashi</a>, was thinking of creating an artbook filled with her illustrations of the Spanish VOCALOID. Now, that dream is closer to becoming a reality with the Kickstarter project &#8220;The Art of VOCALOID MAIKA&#8221;.</p>
<h3>About the Project</h3>

<a href='/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/6ee539b62c9775c6d1a98fd8842f48a5_original.png'><img width="300" height="113" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/6ee539b62c9775c6d1a98fd8842f48a5_original-300x113.png" class="attachment-medium size-medium" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/6ee539b62c9775c6d1a98fd8842f48a5_original-300x113.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/6ee539b62c9775c6d1a98fd8842f48a5_original.png 680w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>

<p>The book will include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Predesigns</li>
<li>Unpublished sketches</li>
<li>Unpublished redesigns</li>
<li>All the art featured in the PVs <a href="http://vocadb.net/S/44228">Que Decida El Corazón</a>, <a href="http://vocadb.net/S/112016">Cosmonauts</a> and <a href="http://vocadb.net/S/80892">Quiero un dinosaurio</a></li>
<li>And promotional arts</li>
</ul>
<p>Noririn will also add new designs to the artbook too, such as the final art from the <a href="/maika-design-contest-for-art-book-announced/"><em>Sky MAIKA</em></a> contest!</p>
<p>Check out Noririn&#8217;s video talking about the project from her <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCJN84_Y0GYWZ9jAesE3oo9w">YouTube channel</a>!</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/e_pb-kps6p4?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Goals</h3>
<p>There are total of five, different goals:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>2500€ (~$2946 USD): </strong>Artbook gets printed</li>
<li><strong>3500€ (~$4125 USD): </strong>Double the quantity of artbooks printed, four new pages, and free postcard</li>
<li><strong>5000€ (~$5893 USD):</strong> More artbooks printed, backers receive exclusive keychains designed for the campaign, 10 more pages added to the artbook</li>
<li><strong>7000€ (~$8250 USD):</strong> Even more artbooks printed, add 10 more pages, guest artists and new 3D exclusive model by <a href="https://adan-yoistyle.deviantart.com/">adan-YoiStyle</a></li>
<li><strong>10,000€ (~$11,785 USD): </strong>Art commissions for the artbook drawn by well-known artists such as <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/9213">KEI</a>, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/15512">Akatsuki Gomoku</a>, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/2230">iXima</a>, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/13499">KKUEM</a>, etc., add 10 more pages</li>
</ol>
<h3>Reward Tiers</h3>
<p><em>Note: Descriptions are taken directly off of the <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/noririn/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika/description">Kickstarter page</a>.</em></p>
<p><em><strong>1€ (~$1.18 USD) or more: Everything is welcome! </strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (digital)</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>5€ (~$6 USD) or more: You&#8217;re making this possible! </strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>15€ (~$18 USD) or more: Enjoy it digitally! </strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Digital version of the Artbook!</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>25€ (~$29 USD) or more: First physical reward! </strong></em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Digital version of the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Physical version of the Artbook!</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>50€ (~$59 USD) or more: Complete pack </strong><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> *only 30 available*</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Digital version of the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Physical version of the Artbook with signed sketch!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>2 random A5 prints!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Set of 4 badges!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Acrylic keychain!</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>75€ (~$88 USD) or more: Sharing is caring! </strong>*only 15 available*</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Digital version of the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em><strong><span class="bold">2×</span></strong> Physical version of the Artbook with signed sketch!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>4 random A5 prints!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Set of 4 badges!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>2 different acrylic keychains!</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>100€ (~$118 USD) or more: Merchan collector </strong>*only 10 available*</em></p>
<ul>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Digital version of the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em><span class="bold">2×</span> Physical version of the Artbook with signed sketch!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>4 random A5 prints!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Set of 4 badges!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>2 different acrylic keychains!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Acrylic figure with stand!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Exclusive T-shirt!</em></li>
</ul>
<p><em><strong>200€ (~$236 USD) or more: I want EVERYTHING </strong>*only 5 available*</em></p>
<ul class="type-14 ml3 green-dark mb2 pl2">
<li class="list-disc"><em>Thank you message! <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.1.0/72x72/2665.png" alt="♥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Your name will appear in the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Digital version of the Artbook!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em><span class="bold">2×</span> Physical version of the Artbook with signed sketch!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>4 random A5 prints!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Set of 4 badges!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>2 different acrylic keychains!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Acrylic figure with stand!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em><span class="bold">2×</span> Exclusive T-shirt!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Adorable MAIKA mug!</em></li>
<li class="list-disc"><em>Exclusive original MAIKA art for you signed and dedicated</em></li>
</ul>
<h3>Where to Donate</h3>
<p>You can donate to <em>The Art of VOCALOID MAIKA</em> from the Kickstarter <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/noririn/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika/description">here</a>. The project has until Friday, December 1st by 5pm EST to reach its first goal of 2500€ (~$2946 USD). At the time this article was written, the project is already almost 82% funded. So be sure to donate before the deadline!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika-artbook-kickstarter-has-launched/">&#8220;The Art of VOCALOID MAIKA&#8221; Artbook Kickstarter Has Launched!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/the-art-of-vocaloid-maika-artbook-kickstarter-has-launched/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MAIKA Power and Soft Confirmed!</title>
		<link>/maika-power-soft-confirmed/</link>
					<comments>/maika-power-soft-confirmed/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 18:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female Vocal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spanish Vocal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voctro Labs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=99611/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While many people noticed &#8220;Power&#8221; and &#8220;Soft&#8221; voices available in some of Voctro Lab&#8217;s newest research, the company never specifically said MAIKA Power and Soft were actual voice banks&#8230; until now! A new post from the company confirms that there is indeed a MAIKA Power and a MAIKA Soft. However, please note that these are &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/maika-power-soft-confirmed/">MAIKA Power and Soft Confirmed!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While many people noticed &#8220;Power&#8221; and &#8220;Soft&#8221; voices available in some of Voctro Lab&#8217;s newest research, the company never specifically said MAIKA Power and Soft were actual voice banks&#8230; until now! A new post from the company confirms that there is indeed a MAIKA Power and a MAIKA Soft. However, please note that these are NOT confirmed VOCALOID voice banks. Instead, they are used in Voctro&#8217;s new research. And while these could be VOCALOID voice banks in the future, there&#8217;s no confirmation.</p>
<h3>About the Project</h3>
<p>While <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.03809" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">there&#8217;s a whole research paper</a> available, we&#8217;ll keep things short in layman&#8217;s terms. The project aimed to test how vocal synths would work with a machine programming them versus a human. The research team noticed that current vocal synths can only improve so much and decided to try a different approach. Machine learning, however, usually provided far less realistic results, so the project was made to attempt to get the best of both worlds: the realism of current vocal synths with the flexibility of easier to improve machine learning.</p>
<h3>MAIKA Power &amp; Soft</h3>
<div id="fb-root"></div>
<p><script>(function(d, s, id) {  var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];  if (d.getElementById(id)) return;  js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id;  js.src = "//connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js#xfbml=1&version=v2.3";  fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs);}(document, 'script', 'facebook-jssdk'));</script></p>
<div class="fb-post" data-href="https://www.facebook.com/VocaloidMaikaOficial/posts/1446670535396254" data-width="618">
<blockquote cite="https://www.facebook.com/VocaloidMaikaOficial/posts/1446670535396254" class="fb-xfbml-parse-ignore">
<p>New #deeplearning singing voice synthesis research by Voctro Labs cofounders using Vocaloid Maika voice, you can hear&#8230;</p>
<p>Posted by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/VocaloidMaikaOficial/">Vocaloid Maika</a> on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.facebook.com/VocaloidMaikaOficial/posts/1446670535396254">Wednesday, April 26, 2017</a></p></blockquote>
</div>
<p>Those who visited <a href="http://www.dtic.upf.edu/~mblaauw/IS2017_NPSS/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the samples website</a> clearly heard MAIKA&#8217;s voice in the Spanish samples. There are &#8220;Mix,&#8221; &#8220;Acapella,&#8221; &#8220;Soft VQ,&#8221; and &#8220;Power VQ&#8221; samples available. However, the Soft and Power VQs weren&#8217;t confirmed to be different banks. For all we knew, the machine could have learned to manipulate the voices to create more powerful or softer vocals.</p>
<p>As noted earlier, these are NOT confirmed VOCALOID voice banks. While we won&#8217;t rule out the possibility, we also can&#8217;t guarantee it.</p>
<p>Instead, all we can do is wait. MAIKA doesn&#8217;t have a V4 update yet, so there is a possibility. However, the chance that these voices were just for the research is also a high possibility.</p>
<h3>More Information</h3>
<p><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1704.03809" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Research Paper</a><br />
<a href="http://www.dtic.upf.edu/~mblaauw/IS2017_NPSS/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Vocal Samples</a> (Please note that the English samples are NOT confirmed to be any available or upcoming voice banks!)<br />
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/VocaloidMaikaOficial/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Official MAIKA Facebook</a><br />
<a href="https://www.facebook.com/VoctroLabs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Voctro Labs Official Facebook</a></p>
<p>And, as always, stay tuned to VNN for more updates!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/maika-power-soft-confirmed/">MAIKA Power and Soft Confirmed!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/maika-power-soft-confirmed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
