<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Crypton Reveals Plan for New Singing Software in 2020!	</title>
	<atom:link href="/crypton-reveals-plan-for-new-singing-software-in-2020/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/crypton-reveals-plan-for-new-singing-software-in-2020/</link>
	<description>Everything about virtual voices, just one click away!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 01:53:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: The Crypton/Vocaloid Split #1 (Reemsborko Agency) &#124; VocaloiDemo		</title>
		<link>/crypton-reveals-plan-for-new-singing-software-in-2020/#comment-66</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Crypton/Vocaloid Split #1 (Reemsborko Agency) &#124; VocaloiDemo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 01:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=242137#comment-66</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] certain live stream that I CAN&#8217;T FIND FOR SOME REASON!!! But to make up for it, here&#8217;s Vocaloid News Network article on it because it&#8217;s a more reputable source, although it doesn&#8217;t link to it either, [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] certain live stream that I CAN&#8217;T FIND FOR SOME REASON!!! But to make up for it, here&#8217;s Vocaloid News Network article on it because it&#8217;s a more reputable source, although it doesn&#8217;t link to it either, [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Riipah Furude		</title>
		<link>/crypton-reveals-plan-for-new-singing-software-in-2020/#comment-65</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Riipah Furude]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 21:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=242137#comment-65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pretty bold move from Crypton. Many fans associate Miku with Vocaloid almost as synonyms. I wonder if the engine is still based on Vocaloid though, just editor is different.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pretty bold move from Crypton. Many fans associate Miku with Vocaloid almost as synonyms. I wonder if the engine is still based on Vocaloid though, just editor is different.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Venova		</title>
		<link>/crypton-reveals-plan-for-new-singing-software-in-2020/#comment-60</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Venova]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 22:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=242137#comment-60</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I would like to note that Piapro Studio in it&#039;s current form is *NOT* &quot;exclusive&quot; to Crypton Vocaloids - ANY Vocaloid 3 or 4 can be loaded into it - including ones from other companies - additionally v2&#039;s imported into Yamaha&#039;s Vocaloid 3 Editor can also be used through Piapro Studio. My first original song (Trading Sanity for Fantasy) was performed by Maika (from Voctro-Labs) in Piapro Studio, as I do not own the Vocaloid Editor. You simply have to go through a web-auth process to get a code to enable the 3rd party Vocaloid to work in Piapro Studio. This will change in the future probably of course if Crypton fully drops Vocaloid compatibility but for now with all currently available Crypton Vocaloids (which all include Piapro Studio); Piapro will work just fine with Vocaloids from any other company. Crypton has been working on a standalone (non-vst plugin) version of Piapro for a while now (early version is available with Miku v4cn). As forthe exclusivity - it&#039;s true that you can only get access to Piapro Studio by buying a Crypton Vocaloid, but once you have it you can use it with any other company&#039;s Vocaloids without issue (Vocaloid engine runtime version considered - backwards compatible is fine but for example you can&#039;t load a v4 from anyone into Piapro if you only have Meiko v3, as the included Piapro and Vocaloid engine runtime is for v3 and cant support v4) - anyways sorry I just wanted it to be known that Piapro works very well with other companies Vocaloids it&#039;s not limited to only Cryptons - you just have to own one of them v3 or v4 to get access to the included Piapro Studio editor (and ofc they also bundle the Studio One daw so the user has everything they need upfront to make fully original songs - both bgm and vocal)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I would like to note that Piapro Studio in it&#8217;s current form is *NOT* &#8220;exclusive&#8221; to Crypton Vocaloids &#8211; ANY Vocaloid 3 or 4 can be loaded into it &#8211; including ones from other companies &#8211; additionally v2&#8217;s imported into Yamaha&#8217;s Vocaloid 3 Editor can also be used through Piapro Studio. My first original song (Trading Sanity for Fantasy) was performed by Maika (from Voctro-Labs) in Piapro Studio, as I do not own the Vocaloid Editor. You simply have to go through a web-auth process to get a code to enable the 3rd party Vocaloid to work in Piapro Studio. This will change in the future probably of course if Crypton fully drops Vocaloid compatibility but for now with all currently available Crypton Vocaloids (which all include Piapro Studio); Piapro will work just fine with Vocaloids from any other company. Crypton has been working on a standalone (non-vst plugin) version of Piapro for a while now (early version is available with Miku v4cn). As forthe exclusivity &#8211; it&#8217;s true that you can only get access to Piapro Studio by buying a Crypton Vocaloid, but once you have it you can use it with any other company&#8217;s Vocaloids without issue (Vocaloid engine runtime version considered &#8211; backwards compatible is fine but for example you can&#8217;t load a v4 from anyone into Piapro if you only have Meiko v3, as the included Piapro and Vocaloid engine runtime is for v3 and cant support v4) &#8211; anyways sorry I just wanted it to be known that Piapro works very well with other companies Vocaloids it&#8217;s not limited to only Cryptons &#8211; you just have to own one of them v3 or v4 to get access to the included Piapro Studio editor (and ofc they also bundle the Studio One daw so the user has everything they need upfront to make fully original songs &#8211; both bgm and vocal)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
