<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Vocalina Archives - VNN</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/vocalina/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Everything about virtual voices, just one click away!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 02:04:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-VNNLOGOSQUARE3-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Vocalina Archives - VNN</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Vocalina YouTube is Active Again!</title>
		<link>/vocalina-youtube-active/</link>
					<comments>/vocalina-youtube-active/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 05:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vocalina]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=77020/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>About a week ago, the official YouTube channel for the Korean text-to-speech singing synthesizer &#8220;Vocalina&#8221; began uploading videos. After looking into things some more, it seems the synth may be making a comeback! The YouTube Uploads The official Vocalina YouTube has been uploading videos for about a week now. As of the time of writing &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocalina-youtube-active/">The Vocalina YouTube is Active Again!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>About a week ago, the official YouTube channel for the Korean text-to-speech singing synthesizer &#8220;Vocalina&#8221; began uploading videos. After looking into things some more, it seems the synth may be making a comeback!</p>
<h3>The YouTube Uploads</h3>
<p>The official <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHUttWqh57r23fEwOhct1lg" target="_blank">Vocalina YouTube</a> has been uploading videos for about a week now. As of the time of writing this article, 8 original songs and 7 covers have been uploaded. Of these covers, a few are Korean covers of rather popular Japanese VOCALOID songs!</p>
<p>The first upload is an original song featuring both of the Vocalina voice banks, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/16300" target="_blank">Khylin</a> and <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/15877" target="_blank">VORRA</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ARPe6C6iitE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>In the description of the video is a word from the previous manager of the channel. Please note that this is a rough translation and may be slightly different.</p>
<blockquote><p><span id="result_box" class="" lang="en"><span title="안녕하세요.">Good morning. </span><span title="3년동안 업데이트 되지 않은 보카리나 티비를 기다려주셔서 감사합니다. ">Thank you for your patience with Vocalina TV, which has not been updated for three years.<br />
</span><span title="저는 그동안 보카리나 티비를 업데이트한 티젠스 측이 아니라 ">I have not been on the side of 티젠스 who updated Vocalina TV.<br />
</span><span title="보카리나 팬카페(보카리나 클럽)를 이번 1월 3일부터 맡게 된 새 매니저 아누시카라고 합니다. ">The Vocalina Fan Cafe (VocalinaClub) has a new manager, Anushika (<span class="_5yl5">아누시카)</span>, who took over starting on January 3rd.</span></span></p>
<p><span title="그동안 티젠스가 많이 힘들어서 그런지 유튜브 계정까지 관리하기는 힘들 것 같아 제가 이렇게 재능기부(?)를 하게 되었습니다. ">I have not been able to manage YouTube accounts and I have had a lot of difficulties.<br />
</span><span title="티젠스 측에서 직접 넘겨받은 것이고 해킹이 아니니 안심하셔도 됩니다. ">You can be rest assured that the account was handed directly from 티젠스 and is not a hack.<br />
</span><span title="기존의 보카리나티비와 다른 보카리나 티비2라고 보시면 될 듯 합니다. ">You can see it as Vocalina TV and VocalinaTV 2.<br />
</span><span title="아울러 광고는 데모곡을 제외하고 모두 제작자님께 허락받고 다는 것이고 ">In addition, all the videos posted except for the demo songs have permission from the producers to post here.<br />
</span><span title="당분간은 티젠스와 보카리나 이용자님들을 위한 이용권 지원이라든지...등에 쓰일 듯 합니다. ">For the time being, this channel seems to be used for the support of Vocalina users.<br />
</span><span class="_5yl5">If we get a big hit&#8230; we are going to share this with the producers&#8230;<br />
Before that, let me update&#8230; nevermind.</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Could this be hinting at an update about Vocalina? Or is it just a little joke? Only time will tell!</p>
<h3>About Vocalina</h3>
<p>Vocalina is a Korean text-to-speech singing synthesizer. It currently features two female vocals, though one has since been retired. VORA is not compatible with the latest update, leaving only Khylin available on the newest version.</p>
<p>Vocalina was developed in late 2011 with VORA as its first voice bank. While SeeU was released around this time, the two actually didn&#8217;t compete much. They even performed in a concert together!</p>
<p>Vocalina&#8217;s 5th anniversary was on December 18th, 2015, and an event was held to celebrate it. However, this was the first update in quite a while. While the software has seen several upgrades, it&#8217;s yet to see new voice banks or have VORA re-added.</p>
<h3>More Information</h3>
<p>At the moment, there&#8217;s not much information on Vocalina. The <a href="http://vocaloid.wikia.com/wiki/VOCALINA" target="_blank">VOCALOID Wiki</a> has a page dedicated to the synth. It covers the two singers as well as the software.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d like to listen to works featuring the Vocalina singers, check out the official Vocalina TV YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHUttWqh57r23fEwOhct1lg" target="_blank">here</a> and be sure to subscribe if you like them! You can also check out <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/16300" target="_blank">Khylin</a> and <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/15877" target="_blank">VORRA</a>&#8216;s VocaDB entries to find more songs featuring the two.</p>
<p>Be sure to stay tuned to VNN for any more information that may surface!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocalina-youtube-active/">The Vocalina YouTube is Active Again!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocalina-youtube-active/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
