<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Weekly Music Recommendation Archives - VNN</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/weekly-music-recommendation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Everything about virtual voices, just one click away!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 16:59:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-VNNLOGOSQUARE3-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Weekly Music Recommendation Archives - VNN</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Weekly Music Recommendations 1/17/2020</title>
		<link>/weekly-music-recommendations-1-17-2020/</link>
					<comments>/weekly-music-recommendations-1-17-2020/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ragyuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 22:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly Music Recommendation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=250114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Good evening! I’m RAGyuo! Welcome to another set of weekly music recommendations! I have so many more songs to offer this week! And I do want to give an apology for why there wasn’t any blogs lately. I’m having memory problems and I kept forgetting to do this blog! But no worries, I’m back to &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/weekly-music-recommendations-1-17-2020/">Weekly Music Recommendations 1/17/2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align: left;">Good evening! I’m RAGyuo!</h3>
<p>Welcome to another set of weekly music recommendations! I have so many more songs to offer this week!</p>
<p>And I do want to give an apology for why there wasn’t any blogs lately. I’m having memory problems and I kept forgetting to do this blog! But no worries, I’m back to share my 5 years of deep knowledge about Vocaloid! So here we go!</p>
<h3><strong>4. <a href="https://vocadb.net/S/71439">Teratoma by apolP</a></strong></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe title="【apolP feat. GUMI】 Teratoma 【Original Song + PV】" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xAGe5iJGvvA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This song is one of the most lit songs I’ve ever heard!! There’s even a remix of this song that hits even harder than this version. Once the beat drops you’re definitely gonna drop on the floor on how hard this beat drops.. to me it did. Now, this producer in my opinion is a one hit wonder because even though he still uploads, only his Halloween songs are an absolute banger. But it’s only in my taste. You might like his songs! So I suggest you check him out!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong>3. <a href="https://vocadb.net/S/3719">clock lock works &#8211; hachi </a></strong></h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="ハチ MV「clock lock works」HACHI" width="618" height="464" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hEyvYm2YRXQ?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>I’m pretty sure you guys know hachi.. other wise known as kenshi yonezu. His early works consists of the most famous Vocaloid songs: Matroyoshka, Panda Hero, World’s End Umbrella, Open close demons and the dead. Now he makes other songs using his beautiful voice called Peace Sign (And as a boku no hero academia fan you should know) and Lemon. But this song to me is a personal favorite of his. It sounds so simple, but it really gives me nostalgic moments even though I’ve never listened to this song before 2015. Out of all of his songs, this song is my #1 favorite&#8230; besides world’s end umbrella. Well, that’s tied in my eyes. Definitely check out hachi’s lesser known songs they’re really awesome!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3><strong> 2.<a href="https://vocadb.net/S/5240"> for Campanella &#8211; sasakure.UK </a></strong></h3>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="sasakure.UK - For Campanella feat. GUMI / カムパネルラ" width="618" height="464" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HgJmRGl4YLc?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>For Sasakure, campanella is one of my favorite songs as it gives me complete nostalgic moments and it reminds me of when I was 6 or 7. This is one of my personal favorite songs, but not my favorite song. sasakure.UK is very known for his chiptune songs with his most famous song hello planet, then 39 (Collab with Deco 27), and spider thread monopoly. He still makes new songs and I suggest you check his songs out!</p>
<h3><strong> 1. <a href="https://vocadb.net/S/83785">Intracerebral Synapse Rebellion &#8211; sizimi </a></strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.nicovideo.jp/watch/sm25817652">https://www.nicovideo.jp/watch/sm25817652</a></p>
<p>I adore this song!! Super addictive in the middle part!! I could only post a niconicodouga video because they don’t upload on YouTube. They are not a well known producer at all. In fact, this is probably the only song they have made. Even so, I suggest you check out their MyList because their could be more songs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>That’s it for this week! Tune in next week!!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/weekly-music-recommendations-1-17-2020/">Weekly Music Recommendations 1/17/2020</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-music-recommendations-1-17-2020/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Music Recomendations [2] 12/6/19</title>
		<link>/weekly-music-recomendations-2-12-6-19/</link>
					<comments>/weekly-music-recomendations-2-12-6-19/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[ragyuo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 04:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Music Recommendation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=248516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nice to meet you, I’m Ragyuo! Welcome to the Weekly Music Recommendations! I’m glad to be able to give you guys more music recommendations, there’s so many I want to give but I have to limit myself to 5. So first off, 5. I Can’t Die Yet &#8211; 16 164 is known for songs such &#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/weekly-music-recomendations-2-12-6-19/">Weekly Music Recomendations [2] 12/6/19</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div dir="auto">Nice to meet you, I’m Ragyuo!</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Welcome to the Weekly Music Recommendations! I’m glad to be able to give you guys more music recommendations, there’s so many I want to give but I have to limit myself to 5. So first off,</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<h2>5. I Can’t Die Yet &#8211; 16</h2>
<div dir="auto">
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="僕はまだ死ねない／164 feat.初音ミク（公式）" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-d2KqenB5AE?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">164 is known for songs such as &#8220;A Born Coward&#8221;, &#8220;Hated Person Song&#8221; and Reverberation. I’m not a big fan of him myself but others loves his songs, including A Born Coward which is his most famous song.  Sometimes, he makes the most emotional songs I’ve ever heard when it comes to Vocaloid, which is this song and Hated Person Song. I love these songs a lot because of the chorus.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<h2>4. Searching For Your Love &#8211; Kikuo</h2>
<div dir="auto">
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="Kikuo - 愛を探して" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5NnWQOXMpao?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">I absolutely love Kikuo!! I have so many songs I should recommend because to me he is absolutely extraordinary!! This was his last uploaded song and I want people to listen to more of his music! Kikuo is known for &#8220;I’m sorry, I’m sorry, O light&#8221; and &#8220;Love me love me love me&#8221;.  His music varies but keeps the same theme, which I love about his music! I had to keep myself together just to not add more songs of his because this is a variety blog not just 1 producer!</div>
<h2> 3. Yamitsuki / Addiction &#8211; MARETU</h2>
<div dir="auto">
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="【初音ミク】　ヤミツキ　【オリジナル】" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7uiKC1P7__U?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">I love maretu as his music is always like a really cool 8 bit songs. This song surprised everyone because his usual style of PVs is black and white, while this one is colorful. But then again, this song belongs to the rhythm game Kotonoha Project 2nd.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">Maretu is known for White Happy, Mind brand, Suji, Coin locker baby, and his latest song SIU. I suggest you check him out as well!</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<h2> 2. Mislead, mislead &#8211; Omoi</h2>
<div dir="auto">
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="ミスリード・ミスリード / Omoi feat. 初音ミク" width="618" height="348" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7TfohVyOk9A?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">I love a lot of Omoi songs! &#8220;Mislead, Mislead&#8221; is one of my favorites though. Omoi tends to make a lot of catchy songs as well! Omoi is mostly known for his song Teo which you’ve probably heard already. I wish this song could be on Project Diva Mega Mix istead of Teo but that’s ok!</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<h2> 1. Aimaina / Vague &#8211; PinocchioP</h2>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">
<p><iframe loading="lazy" title="PinocchioP - Aimaina / ピノキオピー - アイマイナ" width="618" height="464" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DBTjK5y68jA?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">I honestly love PinocchioP! PinocchioP is one of my favorite producers and he just makes this happy beat songs, that to me is unique in itself. Like, you can definitely differentiate his songs like you can with Kikuo.  This song though, is a personal favorite of mines from him. It’s extremely old but personally, I love it.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">PinocchioP is known for World Common Domination, Slow motion, motivation is dead, I’m glad you’re evil too, Nina, and many more which I can’t list them all. A lot of his songs have over a million views so lots of people have seen his music by now. Aimaina  isn’t so known but should be known.</div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto"></div>
<div dir="auto">That’s it for this! Thank you so much for reading this list and I hope you support these producers!!</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/weekly-music-recomendations-2-12-6-19/">Weekly Music Recomendations [2] 12/6/19</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/weekly-music-recomendations-2-12-6-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
