<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Weekly Review Archives - VNN</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/weekly-review/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Everything about virtual voices, just one click away!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 20:21:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/cropped-VNNLOGOSQUARE3-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Weekly Review Archives - VNN</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review April 4th to April 9th, 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-review-april-4th-april-9th-2016/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-review-april-4th-april-9th-2016/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 23:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The news picked up a bit! There's still not too much going on but now you can have a healthy serving of VOCALOID news. Enjoy your VOCALOID week in review.</p>
<p>Miku News</p>
<p>Miku starts out the news with some nice figures!</p>
<p>Figma Racing Miku 2016 Sponsorship 2nd Round Courses Now Open!</p>
<p>If you happened to</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-review-april-4th-april-9th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review April 4th to April 9th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The news picked up a bit! There&#8217;s still not too much going on but now you can have a healthy serving of VOCALOID news. Enjoy your VOCALOID week in review.</p>
<h3>Miku News</h3>
<p>Miku starts out the news with some nice figures!</p>
<h5>Figma Racing Miku 2016 Sponsorship 2nd Round Courses Now Open!</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/figma-racing-miku-2016-sponsorship-2nd-round-courses-now-open/#sthash.iifDbaVl.dpuf" target="_blank"><img class=" wp-image-6142 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/remiku16figma2_header-768x480-1.jpg" alt="remiku16figma2_header-768x480" width="531" height="332" /></a><br />
If you happened to miss out the Figma Racing Miku 2016 sponsorship courses, we&#8217;re pleased to announce that Goodsmile Racing has reopened the Figma courses starting April 1st. The 2nd round courses will retain the same benefits from the 1st round, and will remain open until June 15th, 2016. For more information, see <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/figma-racing-miku-2016-sponsorship-2nd-round-courses-now-open/#sthash.iifDbaVl.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h5>Nendoroid Co-de Hatsune Miku: Bless You (Breathe With You) Preorders Now Open!</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/nendoroid-co-de-hatsune-miku-bless-you-breathe-with-you-preorders-now-open/#sthash.FU0qWVTh.JvXXfRLN.dpuf" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6186 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/by_gsc-1-1.jpg" alt="by_gsc-1" width="510" height="289" /></a></p>
<p>The next Hatsune Miku nendoroid joining Good Smile Company&#8217;s &#8220;Co-de&#8221; figure line is Hatsune Miku: Breath With You (Bless You) ver., featuring admittedly one of our favorite module designs from the rhythm game Hatsune Miku: Project Diva F 2nd! She was the second in a trio (but now quadruplet) of Hatsune Miku Co-de figures, with the Ha2ne Miku ver. announced just a couple weeks ago. Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/nendoroid-co-de-hatsune-miku-bless-you-breathe-with-you-preorders-now-open/#sthash.FU0qWVTh.JvXXfRLN.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Zyon Android Pre-Registration and Release Date</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6191 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/12970963_873993919376848_4657865863128788385_o-2.jpg" alt="12970963_873993919376848_4657865863128788385_o" width="565" height="318" /></a></p>
<p>The mobile VOCALOID rhythm game Zyon will launch on Android devices April 29th. They have opened pre-registrations and are offering rewards based on how many fans join the pre-registration. The rewards will be based on the amount of pre-registrations, and you can find that event in the article. All you need to do is click &#8220;interested&#8221; or &#8220;going&#8221; and you will be pre-registered for the Android version of the game and receive the rewards. To get all the rewards, more than 20,000 people need to pre-register! There&#8217;s a campaign on Twitter as well. For more information, be sure to see <a href="" target="_blank">our article</a>.</p>
<h3>IA Sings &#8220;Kimi Wa Hitori Nankaja Naiyo&#8221; Acapella for Charity</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6145 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/IaSingleFeature-1.jpg" alt="IaSingleFeature" width="659" height="255" /></a><br />
While IA has covered songs sung by her voice actress before (the most famous being &#8220;Tori no Uta&#8221;), her acapella cover of &#8220;Kimi Wa Hitori Nankaja Naiyo&#8221; (&#8220;You’re Not Alone&#8221;) takes things a step further and even gives fans a new way to listen to 1st Place&#8217;s VOCALOID. And as an added bonus, all purchases of the song go to charity!</p>
<p>For a review of the song as well as information on how to purchase it, see our article <a href="" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Studio Rana Event in Nakano</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6156 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/12938212_984858418234017_5103957707345021317_n-1.png" alt="12938212_984858418234017_5103957707345021317_n" width="591" height="448" /></a><br />
&#8220;STUDIO RANA&#8221; is an event that will feature VOCALOID Rana in Nakano, Tokyo, on April 23rd and 24th. During this event there will be original illustrations, a VOCALOID experience corner, guest talk, and limited merchandise. You will also find merchandise featuring Unity-chan, Flower, and Rana, as their original illustrations are by her illustrator Shindo Kamichi. The voice providers of Unity-chan and Rana will also be present. For more information, be sure to read <a href="" target="_blank">our article</a>!</p>
<h3>Hatsune Miku OMAKASE Box Review</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-6118 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/OmakaseRevFeat-1.jpg" alt="OmakaseRevFeat" width="616" height="300" /></a><br />
Unfortunately, OMAKASE is no more after this final box. However, they ended with something all VOCALOID fans can appreciate: a Hatsune Miku OMAKASE box featuring Hatsune Miku, Kagamine Rin and Len, Megurine Luka, KAITO, and MEIKO. Of course when they promised more than just Miku merchandise, Hoshi hopped on it. It&#8217;s not often that you get merchandise featuring more than just Miku! Find the full review <a href="" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-review-april-4th-april-9th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review April 4th to April 9th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-review-april-4th-april-9th-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review: March 15th to March 22nd, 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-review-march-15th-march-22nd-2016/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-review-march-15th-march-22nd-2016/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 22:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week was so packed with VOCALOID news, I was two days late getting the article out this time... here's your VOCALOID (mid)week in review!</p>
<p>Miku News</p>
<p>Hatsune Miku Magical Mirai 2016 to Be Held September 9~11th at Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Hall</p>
<p>The latest news update for Magical Mirai 2016 has announced the</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-review-march-15th-march-22nd-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: March 15th to March 22nd, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week was so packed with VOCALOID news, I was two days late getting the article out this time&#8230; here&#8217;s your VOCALOID (mid)week in review!</p>
<h3>Miku News</h3>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Magical Mirai 2016 to Be Held September 9~11th at Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Hall</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-magical-mirai-2016-location-and-dates-confirmed-september-911th-at-makuhari-messe-international-exhibition-hall/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5712 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/mm_date_loc-1.png" alt="mm_date_loc" width="596" height="333" /></a><br />
The latest news update for Magical Mirai 2016 has announced the event dates and location! Start setting your travel plans as the event will take place at Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Hall in Chiba, Japan, between September 9th and 11th. Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-magical-mirai-2016-location-and-dates-confirmed-september-911th-at-makuhari-messe-international-exhibition-hall/" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a></p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Expo 2016 Announced for Houston, Texas, and Monterrey, Mexico, Plus More Mexico City Show Times</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-expo-2016-announced-for-houston-texas-and-monterrey-mexico/#sthash.73BbpPlH.dpuf" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-5715 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/me_tex_mex-1.jpg" alt="me_tex_mex" width="596" height="289" /></a><br />
Hatsune Miku&#8217;s 2016 tour across North America isn&#8217;t finished with announcements yet! Two all-new locations have been confirmed: Houston, Texas, and Monterrey, Mexico! This brings the total North America city tour count to ten. Two more show times were also announced for Mexico City. For showtimes and ticket information, see <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-expo-2016-announced-for-houston-texas-and-monterrey-mexico/#sthash.73BbpPlH.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku: Project Diva X Launches Tomorrow for PS Vita! Game Demo and DLC Available Day 1</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-launches-tomorrow-for-ps-vita-free-demo-and-dlc-available-day-1/#sthash.pVK5CfSm.dpuf" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5791 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/Cdvpr4HUIAAVTxm-1.jpg-large-1.jpg" alt="Cdvpr4HUIAAVTxm.jpg-large" width="589" height="334" /></a><br />
It&#8217;s just one more day until Hatsune Miku Project Diva X launches in Japan (March 24th, JST), so it&#8217;s now or never to choose if you want to preorder to receive the extra bonuses! On top of the Aime game card featuring artwork by KEI, preorders will also include a DLC code for the AIR DO collaboration module &#8220;CA Style A&#8221;, which gives Miku a flight stewardess outfit (which is gorgeous!). The code is good for 39 days after the game release. A version with twintails called &#8220;CA Style 39&#8221; will be a famitsu-exclusive benefit via a DLC code included in the April 7th edition magazine (releasing on March 24th). Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-launches-tomorrow-for-ps-vita-free-demo-and-dlc-available-day-1/" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h5>Project Diva Future Tone PS4 Version To Be Split Into Two Versions Totaling 220 Songs</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/project-diva-future-tone-ps4-version-to-be-split-into-two-versions-totaling-220-songs/#sthash.od5F1ylQ.dpuf" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5848 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/div_ft-1.jpg" alt="div_ft" width="637" height="327" /></a></p>
<p>News of Project Diva Arcade: Future Tone’s PS4 port (simply known as Project Diva Future Tone) has been quite for the past while, but an update today from Famitsu Magazine reveals the game will launch in two versions with new titles, which can be combined to create a total of 220 songs and 340 modules. Each “half” of the game can be purchased and played independently, while the second half can be purchased later if desired as an “add-on”. Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/project-diva-future-tone-ps4-version-to-be-split-into-two-versions-totaling-220-songs/#sthash.od5F1ylQ.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Miku (and Crypton) Merch News</h3>
<h5>Piapro Character Themed OMAKASE Box Item Revealed</h5>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5668 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/OmakaseMiku-1.jpg" alt="OmakaseMiku" width="602" height="335" /></a><br />
The Piapro character themed OMAKASE box by Viewster is set to go out on the 25th with subscriptions ending on the 23rd. Two awesome items have been revealed so far as well as all the artists who will participate. Check out the article for the scoop! (Spoiler: There&#8217;s a Miku t-shirt and a Kagamine colored belt.) Read more <a href="" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>MIKU-Pack Vol. 18: Illustrations, Manga, Snow Miku Festival 2016 Report, and More Now Available!</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/miku-pack-vol-18-illustrations-manga-snow-miku-festival-2016-report-and-music-now-available/#sthash.xVneNoIC.dpuf" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5718 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/miku-pack04_head-768x439-1.jpg" alt="miku-pack04_head-768x439" width="520" height="297" /></a><br />
MIKU-Pack volume 18 has been announced! This month&#8217;s issue features a wide range of contents from Sakura Miku&#8217;s history, the Snow Miku festival 2016 report, illustrations by KEI, a Senbonzakura novel, to VOCALOID manga by various artists. For more information on what the magazine includes, as well as pictures and how to get the magazine, check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/miku-pack-vol-18-illustrations-manga-snow-miku-festival-2016-report-and-music-now-available/#sthash.xVneNoIC.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Cheero × Hatsune Miku Portable Battery Can Soon Cheer up Your Low Battery Woes</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/cheero-x-hatsune-miku-battery-bank-can-soon-cheer-up-your-low-battery-woes/#sthash.WOHINLRa.2TJkOh8O.dpbs" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5709 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/EnergyPlus_mini_miku_topimage01-1.jpg" alt="EnergyPlus_mini_miku_topimage01" width="548" height="332" /></a><br />
Batteries in phones these days just don&#8217;t seem to last as long as they used to, so portable battery packs have become common place for many people who use their smartphones frequently. But what about for the avid Hatsune Miku fan? Cheero has announced an official collaboration battery pack that will likely fit your style. Interested in getting one for yourself? Check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/cheero-x-hatsune-miku-battery-bank-can-soon-cheer-up-your-low-battery-woes/#sthash.WOHINLRa.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a> for more info.</p>
<h5>Nendoroid Petite: Hatsune Miku Renewal – Preorders Open!</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/nendoroid-petite-hatsune-miku-renewal-preorders-open/#sthash.BxZish21.dpuf" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5562 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/nendo_renewal-1.jpg" alt="nendo_renewal" width="542" height="307" /></a><br />
The anticipated &#8220;renewal&#8221; of the Cryptonloid petite series is here! With &#8220;Nendoroid Petite: Hatsune Miku Renewal&#8221;, the petite for each character has a fresh look with their more modern VOCALOID 3 &amp; 4 outfits. Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/nendoroid-petite-hatsune-miku-renewal-preorders-open/#sthash.BxZish21.dpuf" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h5>GSC&#8217;s Sakura-Con 2016 Hatsune Miku Figure Sales</h5>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5720 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/GSC_sakuraCon_figures-1.jpg" alt="GSC_sakuraCon_figures" width="557" height="310" /></a><br />
Good Smile Company recently announced over on Mamitan&#8217;s blog some of the figures that they will be selling at Sakura-Con 2016. As always, they have a limited but good selection of figures available for purchase, which includes some Hatsune Miku figures. As of right now, a total of six Hatsune Miku figures (two figmas and four Nendoroids) will be for sale at Sakura-Con 2016. If you plan to be at Sakura-Con or know a friend who will be, be sure to check out <a href="" target="_blank">our article</a> so you know what figures will be available!</p>
<h3>Yuzuki Yukari and AHS News</h3>
<h5>AHS &#8220;Songs Love&#8221; Concert Footage Released</h5>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5773 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/AHS_cover-1.jpg" alt="AHS_cover" width="557" height="310" /></a><br />
Recently, AHS released a video with commentary on their live stream channel showcasing the AHS &#8220;Songs Love&#8221; concert they hosted featuring the AHS VOCALOIDs. As mentioned in a previous article, on Febuary 28th 2016, AHS held a live VOCALOID concert titled &#8220;Songs Love&#8221; in Japan. The concert featured all of the AHS VOCALOIDs and took place at Kawasaki City Industries Promotional Hall in Kanagawa. For screenshots as well as a link to where you can watch the released footage, see out article <a href="" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>Mamama Yuzuki Yukari MMD Model Released!</h5>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-5753 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/MamamaYukariModel-1.jpg" alt="MamamaYukariModel" width="588" height="327" /></a><br />
After being teased in a previous live stream filled with Yuzki Yukari items, the much awaited Mamama Yuzuki Yukari MMD Model has finally been released! The model is available as a free download on Bowlroll. For terms of use and where to download the model, please see <a href="" target="_blank">our article</a>.</p>
<h3>Macne Nana Teaser Website</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5821 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/NanaSecondCard-1.jpg" alt="NanaSecondCard" width="554" height="309" /></a><br />
A Macne Nana teaser has taken over <a href="http://macne.net/" target="_blank">macne.net</a>. At the moment, the page is &#8220;Loading&#8221; with cards being revealed at certain intervals. These cards are said to hint at something special. With the &#8220;4&#8221; card revealed, some fans are speculating a Macne Nana VOCALOID 4 update. The second card appears to be a &#8220;P of aces&#8221;. While not an actual card, perhaps the suits have something to do with the hints? We&#8217;re still guessing.</p>
<p>This week actually saw two articles concerning the Nana teaser website. For the first one which describes what&#8217;s going on, see <a href="" target="_blank">here</a>. The second one, which describes theories around the second card, can be found <a href="" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Zero-G VOCALOID Sale</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5585 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/zero-g_vocaloid_sale_new-1.jpg" alt="zero-g_vocaloid_sale_new" width="558" height="311" /></a><br />
Zero-G, the company most recently known for creating the VOCALOID 4 voice banks Dex and Daina, has announced recently that all of their VOCALOID titles are now on sale! This Zero-G VOCALOID sale marks the lowest prices that these VOCALOIDs have ever been. If you&#8217;re looking to buy a good quality English VOCALOID, now is your chance! Pricing as well as demos of all the VOCALOIDs and more information can be found in <a href="" target="_blank">our article</a>.</p>
<h3>Stardust Collaboration With &#8220;MUSYNC&#8221; Is Now Available on Latest Update!</h3>
<p><a href="" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-5600 aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/12631566_1194640320565845_1557874057800847304_n-1.jpg" alt="stardust_musync" width="555" height="398" /></a><br />
One of the songs from Stardust&#8217;s album collection &#8220;Twinkle Star&#8221; is now available on the mobile rhythm game MUSYNC! This Stardust collaboration with MUSYNC promises to bring us lots of great content in the future. See <a href="" target="_blank">our article</a> for more information.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-review-march-15th-march-22nd-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: March 15th to March 22nd, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-review-march-15th-march-22nd-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review: March 7th to March 14th, 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-in-review-march-7th-march-14th-2016/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-in-review-march-7th-march-14th-2016/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 12:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayduxz.cl/vnn/?p=5515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>March 9th (3/9) was Miku Day, which led to quite a bit of Miku news this week as well. However, we've seen activity from the Chinese VOCALOIDs plus that Yuzuki Yukari Lin figure we mentioned before going up for preorder. Here's your VOCALOID week in review!</p>
<p>Miku News</p>
<p>Since there's so much Miku news, we're</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-march-7th-march-14th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: March 7th to March 14th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>March 9th (3/9) was Miku Day, which led to quite a bit of Miku news this week as well. However, we&#8217;ve seen activity from the Chinese VOCALOIDs plus that Yuzuki Yukari Lin figure we mentioned before going up for preorder. Here&#8217;s your VOCALOID week in review!</p>
<h3>Miku News</h3>
<p>Since there&#8217;s so much Miku news, we&#8217;re gonna get it out of the way right at the start! This week, we&#8217;ve seen everything from Miku themed marriage registration papers to Miku making it into an Australian newspaper.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Themed Marriage Registration Papers</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/share-your-miku-love-with-your-special-someone-with-official-hatsune-miku-themed-marriage-registration-papers" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5349" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/safe_image.jpg" alt="safe_image" width="567" height="298" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/safe_image.jpg 693w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/safe_image-300x158.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 567px) 100vw, 567px" /></a><br />
Do you and your special partner share your passion and love for Hatsune Miku as much as you do for each other? When the time comes to make your life-long relationship official, your love for Miku can also be made official at the same time with new official Hatsune Miku themed marriage registration papers. For pictures and more information on this interesting collaboration, check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/share-your-miku-love-with-your-special-someone-with-official-hatsune-miku-themed-marriage-registration-papers" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku: Magical Mirai 2016 Officially Announced</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-magical-mirai-2016-officially-announced/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5346" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/mikumirai-768x362.png" alt="mikumirai-768x362" width="567" height="267" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/mikumirai-768x362.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/mikumirai-768x362-300x141.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 567px) 100vw, 567px" /></a><br />
If you were wondering if Magical Mirai, the holy grail of Hatsune Miku events, would happen in 2016 with all of the Miku Expo tour locations announced, wonder no more. Hatsune Miku: Magical Mirai 2016 is now officially confirmed! But for now, that&#8217;s basically it.</p>
<p>Besides confirmation, details regarding the event location and dates are still unknown. Expect this information to be announced over the next few months. If they follow tradition, however, we can expect the event to take place in late summer, sometime around Hatsune Miku&#8217;s birthday, which occurs on August 31st.</p>
<p>Source: <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-magical-mirai-2016-officially-announced/" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a></p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Expo Taiwan Tour: Main Visual, Overseas Ticket Sales, and CM Published</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-expo-taiwan-tour-main-visual-overseas-ticket-sales-and-cm-published" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5519" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/mikuexpo_taiwan_banner-768x442.jpg" alt="mikuexpo_taiwan_banner-768x442" width="584" height="336" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/mikuexpo_taiwan_banner-768x442.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/mikuexpo_taiwan_banner-768x442-300x173.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 584px) 100vw, 584px" /></a><br />
The main visual for MIKU EXPO 2016 in Taiwan has been published! This year is an exciting one as MIKU EXPO hit several locations around the globe starting with Japan in late March to April, North America in late April to May, and Taiwan on June 25th~26th.</p>
<p>The ticket sales for the Taiwan tour have begun and will close on April 11th or until they&#8217;re sold out. The seats are divided into four areas: VIP for 5,000 yuan ($770), A for 5,000 yuan ($770), B for 3,500 yuan ($539), and C for 2,500 yuan ($385).</p>
<p>For information on how to get tickets if you&#8217;re not in Taiwan as well as the commercial for Miku Expo Taiwan, please see <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-expo-taiwan-tour-main-visual-overseas-ticket-sales-and-cm-published" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku &amp; Vocaloid Phenomenon Now an Official Textbook Study at Oxford University</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/vocaloid-phenomenon-now-an-official-textbook-study-at-oxford-university/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5329" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/maxresdefault-1.jpg" alt="maxresdefault (1)" width="537" height="302" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/maxresdefault-1.jpg 693w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/maxresdefault-1-300x169.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 537px) 100vw, 537px" /></a><br />
While the teaching of Vocaloid software in schools is something that&#8217;s been around for a while, it&#8217;s not too often you see the Hatsune Miku and Vocaloid phenomena studied at universities. In particular, it is being studied at the oldest and most well-known English university in the world: the University of Oxford.</p>
<p>The book is titled &#8220;The Oxford Handbook of Music and Virtuality&#8221;, and the juicy bits relating to Vocaloid can be found under part two.</p>
<p>For more information including chapter titles, what the chapters include, and even where you can read some of the book for free, check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/vocaloid-phenomenon-now-an-official-textbook-study-at-oxford-university/" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Appears in &#8220;The Australian&#8221; Newspaper</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-appears-in-the-australian-newspaper/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="wp-image-5326 aligncenter" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/miku_theau_head.jpg" alt="miku_theau_head" width="539" height="316" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/miku_theau_head.jpg 693w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/miku_theau_head-300x176.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 539px) 100vw, 539px" /></a><br />
Hatsune Miku appearing in major news/media is always interesting to see, and we recently discovered a publication in a major Australia newspaper &#8220;The Australian&#8221;. Teased on the front page of the paper, the article occupies an entire page of the Arts section. The editorial was published on March 1st, 2016.</p>
<p>For more information on the article including where you can read it, go see the full article at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-appears-in-the-australian-newspaper/" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Figure News</h3>
<p>This week saw two figure announcements: one figure up for preorder and another one getting ready to be put up for preorder. And by &#8220;getting ready&#8221;, we mean head over to GSC&#8217;s online shop tomorrow because they&#8217;re going up on March 15th.</p>
<h5>GSC’s Kahotan Reviews Nendoroid Petite: Hatsune Miku Renewal, Preorders Open March 15th</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/gscs-kahotan-reviews-nendoroid-petite-hatsune-miku-renewal-preorders-open-march-15th/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5332" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/npvf_12.jpg" alt="npvf_12" width="515" height="233" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npvf_12.jpg 515w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/npvf_12-300x136.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 515px) 100vw, 515px" /></a></p>
<p>Kahotan from Good Smile Company has released a review on Nendoroid Petite: Hatsune Miku Renewal, a collection of six miniature Vocaloids including Hatsune Miku V3, Kagamine Rin &amp; Len V4X, Megurine Luka V4X, MEIKO V3, KAITO V3, and one secret character!</p>
<p>Each stands at 65 mm tall, slightly smaller than the standard Nendoroid height of 10 cm.</p>
<p>For pictures as well as a link to Kahotan&#8217;s review, head over to <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/gscs-kahotan-reviews-nendoroid-petite-hatsune-miku-renewal-preorders-open-march-15th/" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Yuzuki Yukari Lin 1/8 Scaled Figure Now Available for Preorder!</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/yuzuki-yukari-lin-18-scaled-figure-now-available-for-preorder/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5364" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/yukari_rin_figure_featured_image.jpg" alt="yukari_rin_figure_featured_image" width="566" height="315" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/yukari_rin_figure_featured_image.jpg 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/yukari_rin_figure_featured_image-300x167.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/yukari_rin_figure_featured_image-1024x570.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/yukari_rin_figure_featured_image-1100x612.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 566px) 100vw, 566px" /></a><br />
The Yuzuki Yukari Lin 1/8 scaled figure is now available for preorder! The figure was <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/concerts-a-figure-and-other-yuzuki-yukari-merchandise-announced/" target="_blank">originally announced</a> near the end of 2015 during a live stream held by <a title="" href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/192" target="_blank">AH-Software</a> and then <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/winter-wonder-festival-2016-vocaloid-highlights/" target="_blank">recently teased</a> at Winter Wonfes 2016 fully painted. Read more (and see more pictures plus information on how to preorder) <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/yuzuki-yukari-lin-18-scaled-figure-now-available-for-preorder/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Chinese VOCALOID News</h3>
<p>Luo Tianyi has been confirmed to be receiving a V4 update and another Stardust demo was released!</p>
<h5>Luo Tianyi V4 Update</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/luo-tianyi-vocaloid-4-update/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/tianyi_V4-1.jpg" alt="" width="588" height="218" /></a><br />
Vsinger announced on Weibo that the Luo Tianyi VOCALOID 4 update is official. They confirmed that they already made an appointment with her voice provider ShanXin for her V4 voice bank recording. Although leaks and rumours about Tianyi V4 had been spreading in the Chinese fandom since 2015, this is the first time Vsinger has made an official announcement about the update. Vsinger engineer 人形兔 had also hinted that she will receive an append voice bank as well. For more information, head over to our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/luo-tianyi-vocaloid-4-update/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>New Stardust Demo Released!</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/new-stardust-demo-released/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5438" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/StarStart1.png" alt="StarStart1" width="555" height="311" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/StarStart1.png 1023w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/StarStart1-300x168.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 555px) 100vw, 555px" /></a><br />
Quadimension has brought us another Stardust demo hailing from her first album. This time, we get to listen to &#8220;星之伊始&#8221; (&#8220;Start of the Star&#8221;). This song was first featured in the album crossfade with a still image but the video of the full song contains an animated PV! To watch the video as well as read more about the newest demo and its PV, check out our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/new-stardust-demo-released/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Contest News</h3>
<p>One contest ended and another began. We have the IA and ONE illustration contest which has ended while a contest featuring Vsinger&#8217;s female VOCALOIDs is now happening.</p>
<h5>VSinger VOCALOIDs Spring Costume Design Contest</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/vsinger-vocaloids-spring-costume-design-contest/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/QQE59BBEE7898720150920154338-1.jpg" alt="" width="559" height="193" /></a><br />
As February ends and spring draws near, it&#8217;s time for VSinger girls to get some new clothes for the new season! And what better way to give the girls new clothes than to hold a spring costume design contest?</p>
<p>VSinger is collaborating with the costume selling company AScosing and the ACG community website BCY.net&#8217;s painting section to hold a spring costume design contest for the female VSinger VOCALOIDs Luo Tianyi, YANHE, YueZheng Ling, and Mo QingXian.</p>
<p>You know the drill. More information in our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/vsinger-vocaloids-spring-costume-design-contest/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>IA and ONE First Anniversary Illustration Contest Ends</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5365" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/AniversarryIllustrationsF.png" alt="AniversarryIllustrationsF" width="1145" height="637" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/AniversarryIllustrationsF.png 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/AniversarryIllustrationsF-300x167.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/AniversarryIllustrationsF-1024x570.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/AniversarryIllustrationsF-1100x612.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 1145px) 100vw, 1145px" /></p>
<p>IA&#8217;s page recently announced the ending of the IA and ONE first anniversary illustration contest, which we talked about in a previous article.</p>
<p>1st Place received 74 works in total for the contest and thanks everyone for their participation. As a final surprise, they announced that Sidu and Ishifuro participated and that their works will be included in the booklet as well.</p>
<p>For more information, check out our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/ia-and-one-first-anniversary-illustration-contest-ends/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-march-7th-march-14th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: March 7th to March 14th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-in-review-march-7th-march-14th-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 29th to March 6th, 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-29th-to-march-6th/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-29th-to-march-6th/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 15:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayduxz.cl/vnn/?p=5278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week, Miku and Stardust took the spotlight. We got to hear Stardust's album crossfade, learned more about Project Diva X,  saw some new merchandise, and received a teaser for a new MMD model. Here's your VOCALOID week in review.</p>
<p>Stardust News</p>
<p>The newest Chinese VOCALOID Stardust made news in the VOCALOID world this week</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-29th-to-march-6th/">VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 29th to March 6th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week, Miku and Stardust took the spotlight. We got to hear Stardust&#8217;s album crossfade, learned more about Project Diva X,  saw some new merchandise, and received a teaser for a new MMD model. Here&#8217;s your VOCALOID week in review.</p>
<h3>Stardust News</h3>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-album-crossfade-released/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5194" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/StarwishCrossfadeFeature.png" alt="StarwishCrossfadeFeature" width="588" height="327" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/StarwishCrossfadeFeature.png 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/StarwishCrossfadeFeature-300x167.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/StarwishCrossfadeFeature-1024x570.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/StarwishCrossfadeFeature-1100x612.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 588px) 100vw, 588px" /></a><br />
The newest Chinese VOCALOID <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/35966" target="_blank">Stardust</a> made news in the VOCALOID world this week with the release of the crossfade for her first album <a href="http://vocadb.net/Al/16846" target="_blank">Starwish</a>. There will be eight songs in total featuring various genres from ballad to rock, and even a song that sounds quite a bit like salsa. For the track list and crossfade, check out our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-album-crossfade-released/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Miku News</h3>
<h5>Hatsune Miku: Project Diva X Adds New &#8220;Ultimate Medley&#8221;</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-adds-new-ultimate-medley/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5154" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/diva_x_sc_prev.jpg" alt="diva_x_sc_prev" width="500" height="326" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/diva_x_sc_prev.jpg 500w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/diva_x_sc_prev-300x196.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 500px) 100vw, 500px" /></a><br />
You know how every Hatsune Miku: Project Diva game to date has had that one &#8220;boss&#8221; song that is just too difficult to clear compared to the rest of the music set? Thanks to the introduction of the &#8220;medley&#8221; concept, it looks like Project Diva X will also be adding what has been dubbed the &#8220;ultimate medley&#8221;. Want to know what songs will be in the melody that are sure to drive PDX players mad? Check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-adds-new-ultimate-medley/#sthash.PTQMyhA8.dpbs" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku V4Xβ MikuMikuDance Model Teased by REMmaple</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-v4x-beta-mikumikudance-model-teased-by-remmaple/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5159" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/rm_mod_prev.jpg" alt="rm_mod_prev" width="580" height="363" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/rm_mod_prev.jpg 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/rm_mod_prev-300x188.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /></a><br />
The MikuMikuDance modeler named REMmaple, known for his excellent Hatsune Miku V3 model based on official illustrations by iXima, has gone ahead and created his own teaser model based on iXima&#8217;s tentative Hatsune Miku V4Xβ illustration (which happens to make a nice wallpaper!). See more (including a video of the model in action) at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-v4x-beta-mikumikudance-model-teased-by-remmaple/" target="_blank">Mikufan</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Squishable Announced</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/hatsune-miku-squishable-announced/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5283" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/03/MikuSquishFeature2.jpg" alt="MikuSquishFeature2" width="563" height="313" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/MikuSquishFeature2.jpg 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/MikuSquishFeature2-300x167.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/MikuSquishFeature2-1024x570.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/03/MikuSquishFeature2-1100x612.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 563px) 100vw, 563px" /></a><br />
Squishable recently announced a collaboration with Crypton Future Media to make a Hatsune Miku Squishable brand hanging plush. Currently, the item is up for preorder with orders closing in June 2016. You can read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/hatsune-miku-squishable-announced/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-29th-to-march-6th/">VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 29th to March 6th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-29th-to-march-6th/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 22nd to Feb 28th, 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-22nd-to-feb-28th-2016/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-22nd-to-feb-28th-2016/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayduxz.cl/vnn/?p=5141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This VOCALOID week in review is filled with merchandise! Get your wallets ready because there's a little bit of something for everyone. Additionally, get your ears ready because a new Stardust demo was released! Finally, there's a contest looking for original songs featuring Xin Hua. Here's your VOCALOID week in review.</p>
<p>Second Stardust Demo Released</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-22nd-to-feb-28th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 22nd to Feb 28th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This VOCALOID week in review is filled with merchandise! Get your wallets ready because there&#8217;s a little bit of something for everyone. Additionally, get your ears ready because a new Stardust demo was released! Finally, there&#8217;s a contest looking for original songs featuring Xin Hua. Here&#8217;s your VOCALOID week in review.</p>
<h3>Second Stardust Demo Released</h3>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/second-stardust-demo-released/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5125" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/StarWishFeature.jpg" alt="StarWishFeature" width="660" height="367" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/StarWishFeature.jpg 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/StarWishFeature-300x167.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/StarWishFeature-1024x570.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/StarWishFeature-1100x612.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 660px) 100vw, 660px" /></a><br />
The second VOCALOID Stardust demo was recently released, this time using lyrics and tuning to showcase Stardust’s abilities. The song features both lower and higher notes to give fans a taste of her range. Read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/second-stardust-demo-released/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Album News</h3>
<h5>V flower Album &#8220;Once in a Lifetime&#8221; Released</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/v-flower-album-once-in-a-lifetime-released/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5029" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/FlowerAlbum.jpg" alt="FlowerAlbum" width="669" height="372" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FlowerAlbum.jpg 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FlowerAlbum-300x167.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FlowerAlbum-1024x570.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FlowerAlbum-1100x612.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 669px) 100vw, 669px" /></a><br />
A new album featuring both v flower and v4 flower is now up for purchase both physically and digitally. The v flower album titled &#8220;一期一会&#8221; or &#8220;Ichigoichie&#8221; (&#8220;Once in a Lifetime&#8221;) features songs from various producers. Downloads and physical purchases of both versions come with special bonuses. The album has 12 songs on it using quite a few different vocal ranges for the VOCALOID. For the track list and where you can get the album from, head over to the article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/v-flower-album-once-in-a-lifetime-released/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>Last Three Songs for First Fukase Album Announced</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/last-three-songs-for-first-fukase-album-announced/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5117" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/FukaseSongs.jpg" alt="FukaseSongs" width="672" height="374" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FukaseSongs.jpg 1145w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FukaseSongs-300x167.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FukaseSongs-1024x570.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FukaseSongs-1100x612.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 672px) 100vw, 672px" /></a><br />
The final three songs for the first Fukase album were recently announced. As we mentioned before, the first VOCALOID Fukase album, &#8220;VOCALOID Fukase ~THE GREATEST HITS~&#8221;, is set to be released at the end of March. When the album was first announced, we only knew ten of the 13 songs. For more information, including videos of the final three songs, check out the article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/last-three-songs-for-first-fukase-album-announced/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Xin Hua Contest for SOGO Mall Collaboration!</h3>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/xinhua-vs-sogo-mall-collaboration-song-contest/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5057" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/sogo_contest.jpg" alt="sogo_contest" width="650" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/sogo_contest.jpg 650w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/sogo_contest-300x138.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" /></a><br />
Xin Hua will be on the stage of SOGO mall for the Thanksgiving Festival!<br />
A song contest is being held by Facio for their collaboration between Xin Hua and SOGO mall, starting from February 23rd until March 10th, 11:59 PM (UTC +08:00). The winning music will become SOGO’s theme song and the promotion video will be displayed on SOGO mall’s fountain for half a month. If you&#8217;re interested in entering the contest, you can find the rules and how to enter <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/xinhua-vs-sogo-mall-collaboration-song-contest/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Miku Merch</h3>
<h5>Senbonzakura Themed PC Glasses Released by Washin</h5>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/senbonzakura-collaboration-pc-glasses-released-by-washin/#sthash.SGsjvzMe.dpbs" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5019" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/washin_coll.jpg" alt="washin_coll" width="653" height="350" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/washin_coll.jpg 720w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/washin_coll-300x161.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 653px) 100vw, 653px" /></a><br />
You may or may not have heard about the original Hatsune Miku: Project Diva F collaboration PC glasses by Washin, released back in 2013 (we missed writing an article on them!). The collaboration seems to have gone well for them, as they have since released Racing Miku 2014 and 2015 glasses and sunglasses. Their newest collaboration combines their frames with the design theme of Senbonzakura, the highly popular Hatsune Miku song by WhiteFlame. For pictures and more information, check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/senbonzakura-collaboration-pc-glasses-released-by-washin/#sthash.SGsjvzMe.dpbs" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<h5>Hatsune Miku Spring 2016 ver. Happy Kuji (Lottery) Event Now Underway!</h5>
<h5><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-spring-2016-ver-happy-kuji-lottery-event-now-underway/#sthash.RJO86qOX.dpbs" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-5140" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/prize_prev.jpg" alt="prize_prev" width="601" height="425" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/prize_prev.jpg 685w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/prize_prev-300x212.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/prize_prev-163x114.jpg 163w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /></a></h5>
<p>Happy Kuji’s bi-yearly lottery event is again underway in Japan for Spring 2016, with Hatsune Miku and fellow Cryptonloids taking the theme of the prize event. The event works by buying &#8220;lottery tickets&#8221; from any participating store, such as Family Mart and Animate shops. You will instantly win a prize from a random prize tier, with the higher ranked prizes being more rare. There are also prizes for buying the very last ticket from any store! For more information, check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-spring-2016-ver-happy-kuji-lottery-event-now-underway/#sthash.RJO86qOX.dpbs" target="_blank">Mikufan&#8217;s article</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-22nd-to-feb-28th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 22nd to Feb 28th, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-22nd-to-feb-28th-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 15th to Feb 21st, 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-in-review/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-in-review/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 13:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayduxz.cl/vnn/?p=4996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Here's your VOCALOID week in review for February 15th to February 21st, 2016. We have some information on Project Diva X, a bit of merch news, some voice bank news, and even a new MMD model gracing the pages of VNN.</p>
<p>Project Diva X News</p>
<p>Sega has released new details regarding Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review/">VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 15th to Feb 21st, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s your VOCALOID week in review for February 15th to February 21st, 2016. We have some information on Project Diva X, a bit of merch news, some voice bank news, and even a new MMD model gracing the pages of VNN.</p>
<h3>Project Diva X News</h3>
<p><a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-portraits-album-new-songs-and-medley/#sthash.0PQ7wt0F.dpbs" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4961" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/pjdx_7_03-768x435.jpg" alt="pjdx_7_03-768x435" width="610" height="346" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/pjdx_7_03-768x435.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/pjdx_7_03-768x435-300x170.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 610px) 100vw, 610px" /></a><br />
Sega has released new details regarding Hatsune Miku: Project DIVA X today, with the main focus on AR mode, new features in Home, and new songs and medleys. Home in Project DIVA X has come to develop a number of fascinating interaction systems with the characters. Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-portraits-album-new-songs-and-medley/#sthash.0PQ7wt0F.dpbs" target="_blank">Mikufan</a>.</p>
<h3>Merch News</h3>
<p>There wasn&#8217;t as much merch as last week, but there are definitely some great goodies for you to check out!</p>
<h5>Stardust Demo, Voice Bank, Album and Art Book Dates Confirmed!</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-demo-voice-bank-album-and-art-book-preorder-date-confirmed/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4903" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/Capture.png" alt="Capture" width="575" height="353" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Capture.png 609w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Capture-300x184.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 575px) 100vw, 575px" /></a><br />
A release date as well as prices for Stardust&#8217;s voice bank, first album, art book, and a strap were confirmed as well as the release date for her first demo. Our article provides information on the products which are now available for purchase on Quadimension&#8217;s <a href="https://quadimension.world.taobao.com/" target="_blank">Taobao</a>. Read the article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-demo-voice-bank-album-and-art-book-preorder-date-confirmed/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>VOCALOID Fukase&#8217;s First Album Announced</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/?p=4956" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-1390" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2015/09/FukaseDesignF.jpg" alt="VOCALOID Fukase Design" width="659" height="240" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/FukaseDesignF.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/09/FukaseDesignF-300x109.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 659px) 100vw, 659px" /></a><br />
VOCALOID Fukase&#8217;s first album was announced very recently and is now up for preorder! “VOCALOID Fukase ~THE GREATEST HITS~” will be a compilation album featuring 13 tracks with currently ten tracks known. The remaining three will be announced sometime in late February while the album will be released on March 30th. At the moment, no album art has been released. Read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/?p=4956" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Voice Bank News</h3>
<p>This week we saw the release of a new VOCALOID voice bank as well as a live stream from the voice providers of Dex and Daina.</p>
<h5>Stardust&#8217;s First Demo and Voice Provider Revealed!</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardusts-first-demo-and-voice-provider-revealed/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/0066XWZWgw1f15ojch4g8j30qo0go0zf-1.jpg" alt="" width="595" height="372" /></a><br />
Quadimension uploaded Stardust’s first demo song recently as well as announced the opening of preorders for her voice bank, first album, and her art book. They also revealed her voice provider to be the famous Bilibili singer 茶理理 (Chalili). Read more and hear the demo <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardusts-first-demo-and-voice-provider-revealed/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>Dex and Daina Voice Providers Q&amp;A Stream and More!</h5>
<p><a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/dex-and-daina-voice-providers-qa-stream/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4925" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/DexDainaFeatureNew.png" alt="DexDainaFeatureNew" width="581" height="323" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DexDainaFeatureNew.png 1700w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DexDainaFeatureNew-300x167.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DexDainaFeatureNew-1024x570.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DexDainaFeatureNew-1100x612.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 581px) 100vw, 581px" /></a>Recently, EmpathP and Kenji-B held a live stream to talk about the production of Dex and Daina, as well as their future plans for a concert and a rhythm game featuring VOCALOIDs. This stream gave new information as well as recapped old information from the previous streams the two have held in the past. In addition, they talked about EmpathP&#8217;s plans for the VOCAMERICA concert and Kenji&#8217;s plans for a rhythm game. Read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/dex-and-daina-voice-providers-qa-stream/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>MMD News</h3>
<h3> <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/digitrevx-rin-v4x-model-now-available/" target="_blank"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4879" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/DigiRinFeature.png" alt="DigiRinFeature" width="642" height="311" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DigiRinFeature.png 1225w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DigiRinFeature-300x145.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DigiRinFeature-1024x496.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/DigiRinFeature-1100x532.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 642px) 100vw, 642px" /></a></h3>
<p>Fans of the MMD model maker Digitrevx may have noticed that he’s been working on a MMD model based on Kagamine Rin V4X’s design. He finally finished earlier this week and the model is now available for download! Read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/digitrevx-rin-v4x-model-now-available/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review/">VOCALOID Week in Review Feb 15th to Feb 21st, 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review: Feb 8th to Feb 14th 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-8th-to-feb-14th-2016/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-8th-to-feb-14th-2016/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 02:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayduxz.cl/vnn/?p=4856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you thought the last VOCALOID Week in Review was packed with news, you're in for a shocker! This past week held tons of VOCALOID treats.</p>
<p>Merch News</p>
<p>Get your wallets ready because there are lots to buy!</p>
<p>Overseas Snow Miku 2016 Official Goods Store Now Open!</p>
<p>Every year, people who weren't able to visit</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-8th-to-feb-14th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: Feb 8th to Feb 14th 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you thought the last VOCALOID Week in Review was packed with news, you&#8217;re in for a shocker! This past week held tons of VOCALOID treats.</p>
<h3>Merch News</h3>
<p>Get your wallets ready because there are lots to buy!</p>
<h5>Overseas Snow Miku 2016 Official Goods Store Now Open!</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4818" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/shopban.jpg" alt="shopban" width="580" height="310" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/shopban.jpg 580w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/shopban-300x160.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 580px) 100vw, 580px" /><br />
Every year, people who weren&#8217;t able to visit Sapporo for the Snow Miku festivities are given a chance to buy some (but not all) of the items that were available in Sapporo online. The store is now open with various items ready to be purchased. For more info, including a list of items available as of the time the article was written, check out <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/overseas-snow-miku-2016-goods-shop-now-open/" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h5>“ECHO” Novel Promotional Video Released</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4720" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/ECHONovel.jpg" alt="ECHONovel" width="590" height="286" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/ECHONovel.jpg 1298w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/ECHONovel-300x145.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/ECHONovel-1024x495.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/ECHONovel-1100x532.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 590px) 100vw, 590px" /><br />
The novel based on <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/13552" target="_blank">Crusher-P</a>&#8216;s famous song &#8220;<a href="http://vocadb.net/S/68814" target="_blank">ECHO</a>&#8221; finally has a promotional video out. And boy does it look creepy. Though there are no solid plans for an English release, you can preorder the Japanese release and help support the novel. If there&#8217;s enough interest in it, there&#8217;s word that an English translation will be made available. Read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/echo-novel-promotional-video-released/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>U/M/A/A Launched Global Webstore for Various CDs and Merchandises</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4611" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/umaainc_globalsales_banner-1.jpg" alt="umaainc_globalsales_banner" width="608" height="284" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/umaainc_globalsales_banner-1.jpg 1500w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/umaainc_globalsales_banner-1-300x140.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/umaainc_globalsales_banner-1-1024x478.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/umaainc_globalsales_banner-1-1100x513.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 608px) 100vw, 608px" /><br />
U/M/A/A Inc. launched a global online web store for CDs and merchandises in response to the growing demand. The store features various goods by artists such as <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/45" target="_blank">DECO*27</a>, <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/51" target="_blank">sasakure.UK</a>, and <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/28" target="_blank">PinocchioP</a>, and covers worldwide orders and shipping. Read more at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/umaa-launched-global-webstore-for-various-cds-and-merchandises/#sthash.yDdwfPaG.tUHQChik.dpbs" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a></p>
<h3>Voice Bank News</h3>
<p>There&#8217;s been quite a bit of news surrounding the voices of our virtual idols this past week.</p>
<h5>Alter/Ego Voice Bank ALYS Available for Preorder</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4624" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/ALYSPreOrderR.jpg" alt="ALYSPreOrderR" width="623" height="227" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/ALYSPreOrderR.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/ALYSPreOrderR-300x109.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /><br />
The <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/16811" target="_blank">ALYS</a> preorder is 10% off the final release price and is €90.00 inside of Europe. Those outside of Europe can get the voice for €75.00 ($84.94 USD) once they sign up or sign in to their account. Only a digital version is available at the moment with no word on a physical release. Read more and learn where to purchase the preorder <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/alter-ego-alys-preorder-now-available/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>Unity-Chan Voice Changer Program</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4649" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/unti-cover-photo.png" alt="unti cover photo" width="574" height="278" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/unti-cover-photo.png 1298w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/unti-cover-photo-300x145.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/unti-cover-photo-1024x495.png 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/unti-cover-photo-1100x532.png 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 574px) 100vw, 574px" /><br />
Have you ever wanted to make <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/41220" target="_blank">Unity-Chan</a> say anything you can think of without the hassle of the <a href="https://unity3d.com/" target="_blank">Unity Engine</a>? How about making her speak high pitched or sound like a man? Just plug in a microphone, say anything you wish, and she will repeat your every word, laugh, or even repeat the clicking sound of your keyboard. User <a href="https://twitter.com/kaigyoPG" target="_blank">@kaigyoPG</a> has done just that. This is a stand-alone program, therefore you do not need the Unity Engine to use it. Read more <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/unity-chan-voice-changer-demo/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h5>Dex and Daina Voice Providers Revealed</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-444" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2015/06/DexAndDaina.jpg" alt="DexAndDaina" width="601" height="334" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DexAndDaina.jpg 1700w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DexAndDaina-300x167.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DexAndDaina-1024x570.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DexAndDaina-1100x612.jpg 1100w" sizes="(max-width: 601px) 100vw, 601px" /><br />
When <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/36169" target="_blank">Dex</a> and <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/36170" target="_blank">Daina</a> were announced in June, the voice providers for them were not known. However, in November EmpathP mentioned in one of her live streams that she was not sure if they would be revealed before February, and if not they would announce it at Katsucon. This weekend at Katsucon as promised, EmpathP has revealed the voice providers for Dex and Daina at her panel. You&#8217;re going to have to read <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/dex-and-daina-voice-providers-revealed/" target="_blank">the article</a> to find out who they are, though!</p>
<h5>Stardust PV Teaser</h5>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4659" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/02/0066XWZWgw1f0wgyqad2lj30q00epaee.jpg" alt="0066XWZWgw1f0wgyqad2lj30q00epaee" width="578" height="327" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/0066XWZWgw1f0wgyqad2lj30q00epaee.jpg 936w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/02/0066XWZWgw1f0wgyqad2lj30q00epaee-300x170.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 578px) 100vw, 578px" /><br />
The preorders for the new Chinese Vocaloid “<a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/35966" target="_blank">Stardust</a>” will soon be open, and with those comes her demo along with a PV. A short teaser was revealed through the <a href="http://www.bilibili.com/html/bnj2016.html" target="_blank">哔哩哔哩拜年祭 Bilibili New Year Gala</a>. For screenshots and directions on how to get to the video, check out our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-upcoming-pv-teaser/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>IA and ONE Illustration Contest Announced</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-3670" src="https://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/wp-content/uploads/sites/6/2016/01/IAONEFeature.jpg" alt="IAONEFeature" width="623" height="227" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/IAONEFeature.jpg 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2016/01/IAONEFeature-300x109.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 623px) 100vw, 623px" /><br />
1st Place announced an <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/504" target="_blank">IA</a> and <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/31062" target="_blank">ONE</a> illustration contest to celebrate the first anniversary of ONE and the fourth anniversary of IA. 1st Place is accepting illustrations of IA or ONE alone as well as illustrations featuring both of the virtual singers. For the full rules and information on how to enter, read our article <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/ia-and-one-illustration-contest-announced/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-8th-to-feb-14th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: Feb 8th to Feb 14th 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-8th-to-feb-14th-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>VOCALOID Week in Review: Feb 1st to Feb 7th 2016</title>
		<link>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-1st-to-feb-7th-2016/</link>
					<comments>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-1st-to-feb-7th-2016/#disqus_thread</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hoshi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 11:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merchandise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rayduxz.cl/vnn/?p=4080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The first week of February brought with it tons of VOCALOID news. Here's your VOCALOID Week in Review.</p>
<p>Project Diva X News</p>
<p>Character Interactions, Friendship Level, and New Songs</p>
<p>Information on becoming friends with VOCALOIDs in Project Diva X was revealed as well as info on how interactions with those characters raise friendship. In addition</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-1st-to-feb-7th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: Feb 1st to Feb 7th 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first week of February brought with it tons of VOCALOID news. Here&#8217;s your VOCALOID Week in Review.</p>
<h3>Project Diva X News</h3>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/pjdx_6th_8-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-3944"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-3944" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/pjdx_6th_8-1.jpg" alt="pjdx_6th_8" width="640" height="363" /></a></p>
<h5>Character Interactions, Friendship Level, and New Songs</h5>
<p>Information on becoming friends with VOCALOIDs in Project Diva X was revealed as well as info on how interactions with those characters raise friendship. In addition, more songs were added to the list of playable songs in the game. The list includes a medley by <a href="http://vocadb.net/Ar/624" target="_blank">MitchieM</a> featuring songs he&#8217;s produced and &#8220;<a href="http://vocadb.net/S/18479" target="_blank">Hitorinbo Envy</a>&#8220;.</p>
<p>You can also see modules announced as well as more information on these updates over at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/hatsune-miku-project-diva-x-character-interactions-friendship-level-quests-and-new-songs/#sthash.aCeXsLWO.Fl1O4zhO.dpbs" target="_blank">Mikufan.com</a>.</p>
<h5>-DAIBA de DIVA- X Celebration</h5>
<p>There will be a DAIBA de Diva celebration on March 24th to mark the Japanese release of Project DIVA X. Located at the Tokyo Joypolis entertainment venue, “DAIBA de DIVA” events transform the venue into a sort of Hatsune Miku themed park. <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/sega-announces-nendoroid-hatsune-miku-co-de-design-daiba-de-diva-x-event-at-joypolis-arcade-prizes/#sthash.49l8pj10.qhIlSw9H.dpbs" target="_blank">Read the full article</a> (opens in new tab).</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Stardust News</h3>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/0066XWZWgw1ewftr1o8z7j30m806z41i.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-3450"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3450" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/0066XWZWgw1ewftr1o8z7j30m806z41i.jpg" alt="0066XWZWgw1ewftr1o8z7j30m806z41i" width="800" height="251" /></a></p>
<h5><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/stardust-boxart-2.png" rel="attachment wp-att-3987"><img loading="lazy" class=" wp-image-3987 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/stardust-boxart-2.png" alt="stardust boxart" width="324" height="546" /></a>Art Book, New Contest, and More</h5>
<p>Preorders for Stardust&#8217;s official album, art book, and voice bank will open with the release of her demo. Quadimension has also announced a list of artists who are included in the art book. Plans for an official figure have also been announced along with images featuring a 3D model. Finally, there&#8217;s an emote contest going on. Artists are asked to draw emotes featuring Stardust. <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-updates-art-book-figure-new-contest/" target="_blank">Read the full article</a>.</p>
<h5>Release Date and Box Art</h5>
<p>The newest Chinese Vocaloid “Stardust” by Quadimension has had a slight delay on her release date. However, her product page has been opened on Taobao and it appears that we finally have an image of her official box art. Although you cannot purchase her at the moment, she will be available for preorder mid-February and delivery will begin mid-March. Her selling price is ¥ 680.00 ($104 USD), however she is only available through normal means of shipping in China and Taiwan. <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/stardust-boxart-and-release-date-update/" target="_blank">Read the full article</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Figures</h3>
<p>1/4 scale Snow Miku now available for preorder.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/snowmikufig_gsc_banner-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-3945"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3945" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/snowmikufig_gsc_banner-1.jpg" alt="snowmikufig_gsc_banner" width="758" height="361" /></a></p>
<h5></h5>
<p>Need we say more? For more pics and info on where to preorder, click <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/snow-miku-14-scale-figure-now-available-for-preorder/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<h3>WonFes</h3>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/WonFesW2016Feature-1.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-4078"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-4078" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/WonFesW2016Feature-1.jpg" alt="WonFesW2016Feature" width="633" height="370" /></a></p>
<h5></h5>
<p>This weekend marked the big event of the season, Winter WonFes! Figure collectors and lovers flocked to Sapporo (or Twitter if they couldn&#8217;t afford the plane ticket) to see what figure companies were planning to make. While there were also garage kits available, we&#8217;ll be focusing on the official merchandise everyone can order.</p>
<p>Some of the big highlights were the painted version of the Yuzuki Yukari Lin 1/8 scale, the ONE figure, and a new line of Nendoroid Petites called “Nendoroid Petite: Hatsune Miku Selection Renewal”. In addition, the adorable Hatsune Miku iDoll made its debut. Read the full article (and see all the pictures we gathered) <a href="http://rayduxz.cl/vocaloid/en/winter-wonder-festival-2016-vocaloid-highlights/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>New Miku Expo North America Location</h3>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/mikuexpo16na_chicago-768x449-3.jpg" rel="attachment wp-att-3969"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter wp-image-3969" src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/mikuexpo16na_chicago-768x449-3.jpg" alt="mikuexpo16na_chicago-768x449" width="626" height="366" /></a><br />
An eighth location for Miku Expo North America was announced: Chicago! Tickets will go on sale from February 12th at 11:00 A.M. CST. More info can be found at <a href="http://www.mikufan.com/chicago-announced-for-hatsune-miku-expo-2016-north-america-tour" target="_blank">Mikufan</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-1st-to-feb-7th-2016/">VOCALOID Week in Review: Feb 1st to Feb 7th 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">VNN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/vocaloid-week-in-review-feb-1st-to-feb-7th-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
